<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>QEMU Advent Calendar 2014</title>
        <link>http://qemu-advent-calendar.org/</link>
        <description>The latest disk images from the QEMU Advent Calendar 2014.</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>

        <item>
            <title>Day 24 - Go out with a bang</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-24</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-24</guid>
	    <description>This game was custom-coded for the final advent calendar entry.  It's a classic that we hope you'll enjoy (the hint is in the title).  Thank you for following QEMU Advent Calendar 2014, it's been great fun to share an interesting disk image each day.  Happy New Year!</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 23 - Got Pebble?</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-23</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-23</guid>
	    <description>Pebble smartwatch can be connected to iOS and Android devices and runs its own apps.  The emulator for app development is QEMU and the Pebble team have made a preview release available for the QEMU Advent Calendar!  Check out the Getting Started guide for app development in C or Javascript.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 22 - Moon Buggy on s390</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-22</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-22</guid>
	    <description>We can't finish the advent calendar without a System z mainframe disk image.  Here is an ASCII art action game that turns out to be quite fun!  Drive your moon buggy across craters and shoot aliens - a clear task for the mainframe.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 21 - Cult of the Bound Variable</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-21</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-21</guid>
	    <description>The Ninth annual ICFP Programming Contest hosted by Carnegie Mellon University's POP Group was an epic programming puzzle, perfect for the winter holiday break.  This disk image has everything you need to start exploring a series of challenging puzzles into programming languages and obscure systems.  Read the full back-story here.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 20 - HelenOS microkernel multiserver portable OS</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-20</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-20</guid>
	    <description>HelenOS is a modern, general-purpose operating system written from scratch.  It is based on microkernel multiserver design principles.  Core system functionality is decomposed into isolated, intensively communicating and mostly simple user space tasks. HelenOS is still in development and this is a preview of the upcoming 0.6.0 release.  There is a step-by-step tutorial and the HelenOS wiki.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 19 - Mandelbrot in Forth</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-19</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-19</guid>
	    <description>The Mandelbrot set is one of the most well-known fractals.  This demo for PowerPC implements the fractal in Forth so it executes as an OpenFirmware boot script.  You can zoom in/out and move around the fractal.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 18 - Ceph distributed storage system</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-18</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-18</guid>
	    <description>The Ceph open source distributed storage system has become a popular way to provide cloud storage and VM disk image hosting on commodity hardware.  Object storage, block storage, and file system use cases are all supported.  A quickstart guide is available, try ceph status.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 17 - ASCII art demo goodness</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-17</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-17</guid>
	    <description>BB is an ASCII art demo that renders surprisingly smooth effects using aalib.  aalib converts pixel images or movies to ASCII art using the shapes of characters to achieve pleasing visuals.  Matrix digital rain fans will enjoy this demo!</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 16 - Tempest Showroom</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-16</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-16</guid>
	    <description>Tempest Showroom plays melodies on AM radio by displaying specific image patterns.  Back when CRT monitors were the norm, there were concerns about electromagnetic surveillance due to the signals that computer systems emitted.  A related demo is Fabrice Bellard's Analog and Digital TV (DVB-T) Signal Generation.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 15 - Glenda's Christmas</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-15</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-15</guid>
	    <description>Plan 9 from Bell Labs was designed as a successor to Unix.  Some of its key features made it back into Linux, including private mount namespaces, userspace file systems, and UTF-8.  You still need to experience the original where these concepts really work together to achieve an elegant operating system.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 14 - Multiboot "Invaders"</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-14</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-14</guid>
	    <description>The Multiboot boot sequence is supported by the GRUB bootloaders and QEMU as a way to standardize common mechanisms like kernel command-lines, modules/initrd, x86 protected mode, and graphics mode at startup.  This little spaceship game is implemented as a Multiboot-compliant binary so it can be loaded directly by QEMU.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 13 - Second Reality</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-13</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-13</guid>
	    <description>Second Reality is a well-known PC demo from 1993 that combines both 2D and 3D graphics techniques.  The source code was released in 2013.  Try it out and bring the demo to life in QEMU!</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 12 - ETH Native Oberon</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-12</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-12</guid>
	    <description>Oberon is both a family of operating systems and a programming language created by Niklaus Wirth of Modula-2 and Pascal fame.  This image contains the PC Native Oberon variant with an Oberon compiler, network stack, file systems, and graphical user interface.  A parallel universe without UNIX or C...</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 11 - OSv Redis appliance</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-11</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-11</guid>
	    <description>OSv is a guest operating system that eliminates redundant layers of systems software by building a combined kernel, runtime, and application image.  The idea is to simplify management while improving performance.  This disk image includes the Redis key-value store for your NoSQL enjoyment.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 10 - 3 x 512 byte demos</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-10</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-10</guid>
	    <description>Why do things properly when you can attempt them in 512 bytes?  This selection of demos leave no precious byte untouched.  Featuring a ray tracer that spells out "QMU", a software-rendered triangle, and a nyan cat demo to rock your PC speaker with a sweet tune.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 9 - Ubuntu Core, a snappy holiday surprise</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-9</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-9</guid>
	    <description>Surprise, Ubuntu is adding a new member to their family, Ubuntu Core!  The new Snappy package manager makes it easy to share apps or containers with transactional updates.  The whole image weighs in at 110 MB and uses kernel confinement to isolate apps for security.  Say hello to the new cloud guest operating system from Ubuntu!</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 8 - Unlikely marriage of UEFI and Zork</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-8</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-8</guid>
	    <description>This port of the Frotz Z-Machine interpreter allows you to play the original Zork text adventure game on TianoCore UEFI firmware. A significant milestone in UEFI gaming? You be the judge in this showcase of virtual machines without legacy BIOS.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 7 - MINIX 3 under the Christmas tree</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-7</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-7</guid>
	    <description>The venerable MINIX operating system has conquered x86 and ARM platforms with microkernel goodness. Famous for isolating and running operating system components in separate processes so the system can survive failures, MINIX 3 takes pieces from NetBSD userspace so it feels like UNIX - just unstoppable and about to take over the world!</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 6 - 512 byte Julia fractal</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-6</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-6</guid>
	    <description>This tiny disk image renders a Julia fractal in 640x480 resolution 256 color animated glory! Besides using the quaint 256 color palette, this image has a nice sequence of floating point calculations if you want to refresh your x87 instruction knowledge. For a write-up and more screenshots, see this blog post and this one.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 5 - 64-bit ARM has landed</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-5</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-5</guid>
	    <description>QEMU is the first open source emulator with 64-bit ARM support (also known as aarch64). That's right, QEMU doesn't just emulate old hardware, it emulates hardware you may not even own yet! But if you think 32 bits ought to be enough for anyone, just collect your bragging rights for playing tetris-bsd on a bleeding edge hardware architecture.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 4 - Can't spell Christmas without ST</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-4</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-4</guid>
	    <description>Santa has brought you an Atari ST. Get ready for an emulator-inside-an-emulator image that boots straight into the Hatari emulator and the free EmuTOS ROM. This image comes with Atari ST demos for you to enjoy, plus the retro desktop interface.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 3 - Bootable Pi</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-3</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-3</guid>
	    <description>The first image about algorithms (and there are more puzzles to come). How does this tiny boot sector calculate digits of pi? Disassemble with objdump -D -b binary -m i8086 pi.vfd or mount the disk image's FAT file system to view the source.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 2 - Modern DOS</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-2</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-2</guid>
	    <description>This FreeDOS disk image contains the latest and greatest from the land of the Disk Operating System. Besides checking out the DOS TCP/IP stack you never got a chance to use with your 2400 baud modem, you can relive id Software's early shareware hit Commander Keen. As a bonus the freeware edition of Jetpack is also included for crazy jet-powered platform action.</description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>Day 1 - Slacker's time travel</title>
            <link>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-1</link>
            <guid>http://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/#day-1</guid>
            <description>What happens when you dig up the earliest Slackware Linux image to be had? Travel back in time and experience Linux in its early days. And when we say early, we mean kernel pre-1.0 early! The Slackware distribution is the oldest still maintained distribution.</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
